Julia Frances Horan

Phone: (908) 489-7803 | Email: julia.horan28@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/juliafhoran/ | New York, NY 10023 Portfolio: https://juliafrances28.github.io/React/ | Github: github.com/Juliafrances28

SUMMARY

Web Developer with a strong background in Front-End Web Development. Previous experience includes three years in administrative and data management support requiring strong communication and organizational skills. Graduate of Rutgers University with a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MS Office Productivity Suite (Word, Outlook, Excel, Powerpoint), HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Website Development, Application Development, Front-end Development, Database Management, PC and MAC Administration and Configuration

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: Rutgers University, Somerset, NJ

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express,& ReactJS.

Bachelor of Arts: St. Vincent College, Latrobe, PA Major: Communications

PROJECTS

Covid-19_TestingAp | github.com/Juliafrances28/Juliafrances28 | rquiroz32.github.io/Covid-19_TestingApp/

- An application where people can get information on where to get tested for COVID19, including facility information and documentation required to stop the spread of this pandemic.
- Tools used: Materialize.css, HTML, CSS, API's, Javascript, JQuery,

BookBook App | github.com/Juliafrances28/BookBook | pacific-harbor-27397.herokuapp.com/home

- BookBook is an online community created to allow readers who have the same reading interests and live nearby to connect and share books.
- Tools used: UlKit framework, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API's, JQuery

Therefoodathome App | github.com/johnsondavid1107/theresFoodAtHome | theresfoodahome.herokuapp.com/

- An application for users to avoid food waste and encourage them to eat at home. The app helps the user track food
 expiration dates and providing suggested recipes.
- Tools used: Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, React, APIs, Mongoose, FirebaseID

EXPERIENCE

Mass Transit Authority Digital Services | Manhattan, NY

5/2021 - 8/28/2021

Front - End Engineering Intern

- Implementing a webpage with Gatsby using React and the Tailwind framework
- Reviewing the MTA App to ensure it is running correctly with no bugs
- Bring the company in the 21st century in regards to technology
- Participate in team meetings throughout the week

Mass Transit Authority Occupation and Health Services | Brooklyn, NY

12/2018 - 7/2020

Administrative Assistant

- Gathered status reports from supervisors on employees status to confirm testing availability
- Tracked daily attendance of 10-50 employees at required medical appointments
- Inputted random testing information into ACCESS database to verify employee attended test
- Made and received phone calls daily in regards to employees being sent for testing

Barnes and Noble | Manhattan, NY

10/2018 - 12/2018

Sales Associate, Seasonal

- Helped customers locate Books, make suggestions and create store displays
- Finalized customers transactions through the POS Terminal
- Maintained an orderly sales floor, restocked and regulate inventory as needed

Brightpoint Health | Manhattan, NY

5/2018 - 9/2018

Data Specialist

- Managed a data migration project between two database systems
- Performed audit and reconciliation covering data integrity among four EMRs
- Screened patients' records to avoid red flags to ensure information conforms to data validation

NYC Department of Social Services - Office of Disciplinary Affairs | Manhattan, NY

5/2017 - 5/2018

Administrative Assistant

- Performed data entry and data retrieval of case files to the TEAMS database
- Processed incoming/outgoing mail and distributed the mail
- Handled a busy phone line with over 60 calls daily and assisted members of the public with requests
- organized and prepared file folders